Imagine you're playing with a ball. You throw it up
in the air. What happens? It goes up, then it
comes back down, right? That's called projectile motion. It's the
way things move when they're thrown or launched.
Let's break it down. When you throw the ball, you
give it a push. That's its initial velocity. But gravity
is also working on the ball, pulling it down.
So, as the ball goes up, gravity slows it down. Then, it stops for
a moment at the highest point, and gravity starts pulling it back down.
It's like when you throw a basketball onto a table.
It bounces up, then falls back down. Projectile
motion is like that, but in the air!
So, projectile motion is when something goes up, then comes
back down, because of gravity. It's all about that push
you give it and the pull of gravity.